A Guide to the Jonathan Graves Papers, 1807-1847
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Jonathan Graves Papers, 1807-1847
The Library of Virginia
24153
9 leaves and 29 pages
Jonathan Graves
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 30 April 1954, of Fanny G. Crenshaw of Richmond, Virginia.
Biographical Information
Jonathan Graves was born 17 November 1774 in Spotsylvania County, Virginia, to Isaac Graves (1741-1818) and Elizabeth Cowherd Graves (1751-1791). He became a prosperous planter in Orange County, Virginia. He married Margaret Long (ca. 1791-1853), and they had children. He died 14 August 1849 and was buried in the family plot at Pleasant View.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1807-1847, of Jonathan Graves (1774-1849) of Orange County, Virginia, consisting of correspondence to Graves containing letters from his brother Francis Graves (1783-1858) of Green County, Kentucky; S. D. Crenshaw (1787-1859) of Richmond, Virginia; Henry Holcomb of Gallia County, Ohio; John Z. Holladay of Fairfax County, Virginia; and James Vass (1770-1837) of Fredericksburg, Virginia. Letters contain mostly family news or business matters. There is also a prospectus for a newspaper to be published in Fredericskburg titled the Daily Whig News.
Contents List
- Letter, 24 May 1807, from Francis Graves of Green County, Kentucky, stating that he doesn't receive mail from his family in Virginia, informing Jonathan that he has married and acquiring land; and giving the prices of commodities in Green County.
- Letter, 10 February 1812, from Jacob Boar of Rockingham County, Virginia, informing Graves that he has sent him 4 bushels of clover seed and apologized for the necessary delay in sending the seed.
- Letter, 25 November 1816, from Francis Graves stating that his family is well, discussing unrest among slaves in Green County, giving the price of wheat, tobacco, beef, and pork; and stating he sold a horse.
- Letter, 16 October 1821, from S. D. Crenshaw of Richmond, Virginia, concerning his personal and business debts, informing Graves his family is well, and noting the prices of commodities in Richmond.
- Letter, 15 November 1822, from S. D. Crenshaw concerning money owed Graves and extending an invitation for Graves and his wife to join the Crenshaws for Christmas.
- Letter, 25 December 1822, from Francis Graves informing Jonathan that he will be travelling to Virginia to serve as administrator for part of an estate in Amelia County, Virginia, and is hoping to visit Jonathan in Orange County and providing family news.
- Letter, 10 April 1823, from S. D. Crenshaw concerning his purchase and sale of hay and flour.
- Letter, 5 September 1823, from S. D. Crenshaw providing family news, inviting Graves for a visit, commenting that his business is doing well, and giving prices for corn, wheat, and other commodities.
- Letter, 29 February 1824, from S. D. Crenshaw stating that business is doing well and he expects to be able to pay Graves and other more money that he owes, stating he will be in Orange County in the Spring and hopes to see Graves, and giving prices for wheat, corn, oats pork, and bacon, and stating his family is well despite a bout of measles.
- Letter, 2 April 1825, from Henry Holcomb of Gallia County, Ohio, describing his travel through the Kanawha salt works and arrival at Gallia County where he purchased a mill and went into business, and asking that Graves and Crenshaw sell his property in Virginia and send him the proceeds.
- Letter, 12 August 1825, from S. D. Crenshaw stating that he will be sending Graves some sugar, offering to sell him lime, and inviting him for a visit.
- Letter, 27 August 1825, from S. D. Crenshaw providing family news, stating he had sold Graves' wheat and is sending lime, discussing his slaves and his tavern.
- Letter, 16 June 1826, from S. D. Crenshaw stating that he may travel to Kentucky to see land that he has just purchased, providing the prices of commodities in Richmond, and sending family news.
- Letter, 21 September 1826, from S. D. Crenshaw informing Graves that he has a new daughter, and stating that times are hard for businesses in Richmond.
- Letter, 17 December 1826, from S. D. Crenshaw sending the prices for wheat, corn, and tobacco in Richmond, stating that he has bought the property of a hotel, and stating that business is good.
- Letter, 30 June 1827, from S. D. Crenshaw stating that business had been very good, but was now in a lull, informing Graves on the prices of flour and slaves, and discussing the low interest rates on money.
- Letter, 6 July 1827, from S. D. Crenshaw asking for Graves' help in collecting on a debt owed to Crenshaw.
- Letter, 24 October 1830, from John Z. Holladay of Fairfax County, Virginia, concerning a whether a bond Graves signed could be considered usury.
- Letter, 9 November 1830, from James Vass of Fredericksburg, Virginia, concerning Vass' purchase of Graves' wheat and Graves' purchase of goods from Vass.
- Prospectus, 7 May 1847, for the Daily Whig News a Whig party newspaper to be published in Fredericksburg by Lewis O. Magrath, William F. Farish, and James Raines.